(You wished for my demise,)
(تمنيت موتي،)
(yet I disappoint you with my survival.)
(لكنني أخيب ظنك ببقائي على قيد الحياة.)
(And, it all started from a thrush.)
(وبدأ كل شيء من طائر القلاع.)
(Fan Jili framed my elder brother on purpose,)
(فان جيلي لفّقت التهمة لأخي الأكبر عن قصد،)
(causing him to die a wrongful death in prison,)
(مما تسبب في وفاته ظلماً في السجن)
(shattering my family in the process.)
(مما أدى إلى تشتيت عائلتي).
(It has been 13 years since then.)
(مرت 13 سنة منذ ذلك الحين.)
(Every scar I had reminded me of the grudge I could not forget.)
(كل ندبة كانت لديّ كانت تذكرني بالضغينة التي لم أستطع نسيانها.)
(If this is destiny's will,)
(إذا كانت هذه مشيئة القدر،)
(you may leave.)
(يمكنك المغادرة.)
(You're in a rush to leave the sect even though your cultivation is incomplete.)
(أنت في عجلة من أمرك لمغادرة الطائفة على الرغم من أن تدريبك الروحي غير مكتمل.)
(Is it even worth it?)
(هل الأمر يستحق كل هذا العناء؟)
(This is the reason I live,)
(هذا هو سبب وجودي على قيد الحياة)
(even if it means I'll suffer eternal damnation for it.)
(حتى لو كان ذلك يعني أنني سأعاني من اللعنة الأبدية بسببه.)
=To Kill A Songbird=
=لقتل طائر مغرد=
(Adapted from Shen Xiaoguan's Bird Kills Seven People)
(مقتبس من رواية شين شياو غوان " طائر يقتل سبعة أشخاص")
=Episode 1=
=الحلقة 1=
(Shen Guan'er, A Bird Lover, and A Violent Death)
(شين غوان إير، عاشق الطيور، وموت عنيف)
(8th year of Zhenghe) (Gathering Auspiciousness With the Sun)
(السنة الثامنة من عهد تشنغخه) (جمع النعم مع الشمس)
Who is this Divine Lady Thrush?
من هي هذه السيدة الإلهية طائر السمنة؟
She hasn't arrived even though we've been waiting for some time.
لم تصل بعد رغم أننا ننتظرها منذ فترة.
Could it be
هل يمكن أن يكون
that she's a deity?
أنها إلهة؟
I wouldn't dare say that.
لا أجرؤ على قول ذلك.
This divine lady arrived at this land a few months back.
وصلت هذه السيدة الإلهية إلى هذه الأرض قبل بضعة أشهر.
It was said that she possessed supernatural powers.
قيل إنها كانت تمتلك قوى خارقة للطبيعة.
Rumor has it
الاشاعة تتضمن هذا
that she could tell one's fortune with a thrush.
أنها تستطيع أن تقرأ الطالع باستخدام طائر السمنة.
(Xuezhao Residence) Miss.
(إقامة Xuezhao) ملكة جمال.
The guest we've been
(مقر إقامة شويتشاو) الضيف الذي كنا فيه
(Xuezhao Residence) waiting for has arrived.
ينتظر وصوله.
Those who arrived were all investigated by Shiyi.
قام شيي بالتحقيق مع جميع الوافدين .
This is the list containing their background.
هذه هي القائمة التي تحتوي على معلوماتهم الشخصية.
The second-to-last person on the right
الشخص قبل الأخير على اليمين
(Fan Jili, Yahu of Haining County) often seeks out rare flowers and birds
(فان جيلي، ياهو مقاطعة هاينينغ) غالباً ما يبحث عن الزهور والطيور النادرة
for prominent figures in Haining County,
بالنسبة للشخصيات البارزة في مقاطعة هاينينغ،
but secretly does things for them that cannot be seen in the light.
لكنه يفعل سراً أشياءً من أجلهم لا يمكن رؤيتها في العلن.
(Fan Jili,)
(فان جيلي،)
(your fate today)
(مصيرك اليوم)
(has been written for you.)
(لقد كُتب خصيصاً لك.)
(It's time for you)
(حان وقتك)
(to receive your just deserts.)
(لتحصل على جزاءك العادل.)
The divine lady has arrived.
لقد وصلت السيدة الإلهية.
Light the incense.
أشعل البخور.
She has a great figure.
لديها قوام رائع.
My name is Thrush, and I hail from Mount Baiyun.
اسمي ثراش، وأنا من جبل بايون.
Since all of you are here,
بما أنكم جميعاً هنا،
I suppose you know the rules of Mount Baiyun.
أظن أنك تعرف قواعد جبل بايون.
The fortune and destiny of mankind
مصير البشرية وحظها
are guided by the will of Heaven.
يسترشدون بإرادة السماء.
The readings that will be received today,
القراءات التي ستُستقبل اليوم،
no matter if they're auspicious or not,
بغض النظر عما إذا كانت فألاً حسناً أم لا،
must be borne by each of you yourselves.
يجب أن يتحمل كل واحد منكم ذلك بنفسه.
Sure.
بالتأكيد.
If so, Divine Lady.
إذا كان الأمر كذلك، يا سيدتي الإلهية.
Please check how my luck will be recently.
أرجو الاطلاع على كيف سيكون حظي مؤخراً.
An omen!
فأل حسن!
Sir, you will die
سيدي، ستموت
in three days.
في غضون ثلاثة أيام.
Mr. Fan!
السيد فان!
Such lies should not be told.
لا ينبغي قول مثل هذه الأكاذيب.
Did he offend some otherworldly entities?
هل أساء إلى بعض الكيانات من عوالم أخرى؟
Please don't take her words seriously.
من فضلك لا تأخذ كلامها على محمل الجد.
Don't spout such nonsense.
لا تتفوه بمثل هذا الهراء.
Demoness, how dare you spout such nonsense?
يا شيطانة، كيف تجرؤين على التفوّه بهذا الهراء؟
(Come to the locust grove west)
(تعال إلى بستان الجراد غرباً)
(of the town outskirts at the hour of Zi tonight)
(من ضواحي المدينة في ساعة زي الليلة)
(The Hour of Zi, Locust Grove West of the Town Outskirts)
(ساعة زي، بستان الجراد غرب ضواحي المدينة)
Beauty!
جمال!
I'm here.
أنا هنا.
Where are you?
أين أنت؟
Someone died here before.
لقد مات شخص هنا من قبل.
Stop messing around. Show yourself.
كفى عبثاً. أظهر نفسك.
Mr. Fan,
السيد فان،
do you still remember
هل ما زلت تتذكر؟
the person who died here?
الشخص الذي توفي هنا؟
Beauty?
جمال؟
You're here, huh?
أنت هنا، أليس كذلك؟
Why do you look different from how you were during the day?
لماذا تبدو مختلفاً عما كنت عليه خلال النهار؟
Sir, do you like how I look during the day?
سيدي، هل يعجبك مظهري خلال النهار؟
Or do you like the current me?
أم أنك تحبني كما أنا الآن؟
No matter if you're a saintess or a demoness,
سواء كنتِ قديسة أو شيطانة،
I like both versions of you.
أحب كلا النسختين منك.
If so, sir,
إذا كان الأمر كذلك يا سيدي،
please follow me.
أرجو متابعتي.
Beauty!
جمال!
Stop playing hide-and-seek with me.
توقف عن لعب الغميضة معي.
Beauty.
جمال.
Beauty...
جمال...
Fan Jili.
فان جيلي.
Pay with your life!
ادفع حياتك ثمناً لذلك!
Li Ji?
لي جي؟
Why did you harm me?
لماذا آذيتني؟
Li, don't do it!
لي، لا تفعل ذلك!
Don't blame me! Don't hurt me!
لا تلوموني! لا تؤذوني!
They forced me to do it!
لقد أجبروني على فعل ذلك!
Who?
من؟
I don't know!
لا أعرف!
Who is it?
من هذا؟
(Xuezhao Residence)
(إقامة شيوزهاو)
Baoyun Tea, grown on Mount Baoyun in Hangzhou Ge Ling,
شاي باويون، ينمو على جبل باويون في هانغتشو جي لينغ
is known for its calming effects.
تشتهر بتأثيراتها المهدئة.
Divine Lady, the tea you brew
يا سيدتي الإلهية، الشاي الذي تعدينه
must taste better than the dew they serve in the Nine Heavens.
لا بد أن يكون مذاقه أفضل من الندى الذي يقدمونه في السماوات التسع.
Miss,
يفتقد،
County Magistrate Jiang has arrived.
وصل قاضي المقاطعة جيانغ.
Coming.
آت.
What is he doing here?
ماذا يفعل هنا؟
Divine Lady, just ignore him.
يا سيدتي الإلهية، تجاهليه فحسب.
Stay a little longer and have tea with me.
ابقَ قليلاً واشرب الشاي معي.
My head hurts.
رأسي يؤلمني.
Please rest here.
يرجى الاستراحة هنا.
We haven't reported this case to the new county magistrate.
لم نبلغ قاضي المقاطعة الجديد بهذه القضية.
Should we...
هل ينبغي لنا...
Were you referring
هل كنت تقصد
to that good-for-nothing who clings to power?
إلى ذلك الشخص عديم الفائدة الذي يتشبث بالسلطة؟
What's the point of reporting it to him?
ما الفائدة من إبلاغه بذلك؟
So what if he finds out?
وماذا لو اكتشف ذلك؟
Official Jiang.
المسؤول جيانغ.
Arrest this demoness.
ألقوا القبض على هذه الشيطانة.
Yes, sir!
نعم سيدي!
Wait.
انتظر.
Sir, why are you trying to arrest me?
سيدي، لماذا تحاول اعتقالي؟
(Jiang Chun, Country Magistrate) Were you
(جيانغ تشون، قاضي المقاطعة) هل كنتَ
(of Huachang County) the one who said
(من مقاطعة هواشانغ) الذي قال
(Jiang Chun, Country Magistrate) that Mr. Fan
(جيانغ تشون، قاضي المقاطعة) أن السيد فان
(of Huachang County) would die in three days?
(من مقاطعة هواشانغ) سيموت في غضون ثلاثة أيام؟
I was just reading the description of his fate.
كنت أقرأ للتو وصف مصيره.
Did Mr. Fan actually die?
هل مات السيد فان بالفعل؟
How did you kill Fan Jili?
كيف قتلت فان جيلي؟
You'd better confess.
من الأفضل أن تعترف.
When was Mr. Fan killed?
متى قُتل السيد فان؟
This afternoon.
بعد ظهر اليوم.
A woodcutter found a burned corpse
عثر حطاب على جثة متفحمة
on his way to chop some wood.
في طريقه لتقطيع بعض الحطب.
We found an item that belonged to the victim at the crime scene.
عثرنا على غرض يخص الضحية في مسرح الجريمة.
It was Mr. Fan's jade ring.
كان خاتم اليشم الخاص بالسيد فان.
If so, I never had time to act.
إذا كان الأمر كذلك، فلم يكن لدي وقت للتصرف.
Such nonsense. Do you have any alibi?
هذا هراء. هل لديك أي دليل على براءتك؟
This place is so remote that no one ever comes here.
هذا المكان ناءٍ للغاية لدرجة أن لا أحد يأتي إليه أبداً.
It'll be a huge joke
ستكون مزحة كبيرة
if you seek a child in the temple
إذا كنت تبحث عن طفل في المعبد
or an old man in the village to be your alibi.
أو رجل عجوز في القرية ليكون دليلاً على براءتك.
Which scum is daring enough to say that I'm a joke?
أيّ حثالة تجرؤ على القول بأنني أضحوكة؟
(Lu Yanchong, Huachong County Officer) I'm her alibi.
(لو يانتشونغ، مسؤول مقاطعة هواشونغ) أنا دليل براءتها.
(County Magistrate)
(قاضي المقاطعة)
Divine Lady remained at my bedside, not leaving my side for a single step
بقيت السيدة الإلهية بجانب سريري، ولم تفارقني خطوة واحدة.
from the Hour of Si
من ساعة سي
up until 15 minutes ago.
حتى قبل 15 دقيقة.
Divine Lady, I haven't explained myself.
يا سيدتي الإلهية، لم أوضح موقفي.
I'm Lu Yanchong, my courtesy name Jukang.
أنا لو يانتشونغ، واسمي المجاملة جوكانغ.
Everyone calls me Shi.
الجميع يناديني شي.
I'm a local official.
أنا مسؤول محلي.
Shi?
هو؟
Which Shi?
أي شي؟
Naturally, it's Shi, as in beautiful jade and rugged rock.
بطبيعة الحال، إنها شي، كما في اليشم الجميل والصخر الوعر.
(Pure And Righteous Mind, 25th day of the 5th month, 8th year of Zhenghe)
(العقل النقي والصالح، اليوم الخامس والعشرون من الشهر الخامس، السنة الثامنة من تشنغخه)
(Zhenghe 8, 5th month, day 25) (On the 25th day of the 5th month,)
(تشنغخه 8، الشهر الخامس، اليوم 25) (في اليوم الخامس والعشرين من الشهر الخامس،)
(8th year of Zhenghe,)
(السنة الثامنة من عهد تشنغخه)
(dark clouds obscured the sun.)
(حجبت الغيوم الداكنة الشمس.)
(The sky was dark.)
(كانت السماء مظلمة.)
(The anniversary of my brother's death is...)
(ذكرى وفاة أخي هي...)
(13 days left until the 7th day of the 6th month)
(تبقى 13 يوماً حتى اليوم السابع من الشهر السادس)
(Now,)
(الآن،)
(my name is Li Fuyuan.)
(اسمي لي فويوان.)
(This is the second day of my revenge.)
(هذا هو اليوم الثاني من انتقامي.)
(It seems like)
(يبدو الأمر كذلك)
(my nemesis is here.)
(عدوي اللدود هنا.)
♪A thrush's song pierced the endless night♪
???اخترق غناء طائر الشحرور الليل الذي لا ينتهي؟؟؟
♪Blood splattered on the bamboo cage, reflecting the cool moonlight♪
تناثر الدم على قفص الخيزران، عاكساً ضوء القمر البارد.
♪Thirteen years of frost and snow sealed the old study window♪
???أغلقت ثلاثة عشر عاماً من الصقيع والثلج نافذة غرفة الدراسة القديمة؟
♪I twisted the needle, prying open the past♪
???لويت الإبرة، وفتحت الماضي على مصراعيه؟
♪A cold stone marrow presses against my palm♪
يضغط نخاع حجري بارد على راحة يدي.
♪My older brother lay buried afar♪
أخي الأكبر مدفون في مكان بعيد.
♪Flames licked across that place♪
??? امتدت ألسنة اللهب عبر ذلك المكان ???
♪A list of righteous hearts♪
قائمة بالقلوب الصالحة
♪Who laughed in the dark at the panic?♪
من الذي ضحك في الظلام على الذعر؟
♪I'm the shadow caged within as well as the flying light♪
أنا الظل المحبوس في الداخل، وكذلك الضوء الطائر.
♪Only when hatred burns out did we know how scorching our obsessions were♪
لم ندرك مدى اشتعال هواجسنا إلا عندما انطفأت جذوة الكراهية.
♪You said you'd die if you hit a stone♪
قلتَ إنك ستموت إذا اصطدمت بحجر؟
♪Yet you crashed into my fate's web♪
ومع ذلك، فقد وقعتَ في شباك قدري؟
♪Pear blossoms fell all over the wound on your shoulder♪
سقط زهر الكمثرى على الجرح الموجود على كتفك.
♪The wind in the bamboo forest dispersed the hexagrams♪
??? هبّت الرياح في غابة الخيزران فشتتت الأشكال السداسية ???
♪The thrush carried the past away♪
حمل طائر السمنة الماضي بعيدًا.
♪I stood at the end of the fireworks and gaze♪
وقفتُ في نهاية الألعاب النارية ونظرتُ إليها.
♪You lifted a lantern to illuminate♪
رفعتَ فانوسًا لتنيره.
♪That page♪
تلك الصفحة؟